Shao-Chun Ma

Software Engineer

J (+49) 1525-8706794 • 13581, Berlin, Germany justwhenithought@gmail.com https://github.com/cand126 in https://www.linkedin.com/in/shao-chun-ma

Profile

A Java/Kotlin developer with 4 years experience in backend development, based in Berlin. Have permanent EU residence permit. Work with Kotlin, Spring Boot, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL on microservice architecture. Have deployment experience on Kubernetes and AWS. Prefer clean code and complete monitoring system.

Employment History

03.2020 - Now	Software Engineer at SHARE NOW	Berlin
	 Implemented microservices with Kotlin, Java 17, Spring, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL and MongoDB 	
	Built simple frontend applications with TypeScript and Vue 2	
	Migrated Kubernetes services and databases from IBM Clould to AWS	
	Analysed and monitored services with ELK, New Relic, Sentry, Prometheus, and Grafana	
	 Improved CI/CD pipelines in Gitlab, including Helm charts 	
	 Defined SLOs and alerting rules, and envolved in the on-call schedule 	
	 Participated in long-term car sharing in a Scrum team 	
08.2018 - 02.2020	Junior Full-Stack Engineer at omni:us	Berlin
	 Developed microservices with Java 8+, Spring, Python 3, Flask 	
	Built data pipelines with Apache Airflow	
	 Helped data scientists to maintain and deploy AI microservices 	
	 Managed PostgreSQL databases with SQLAlchemy 	
	 Extracted data from XML format to JSON format with Java 	
	 Provided a research proposal about Apache Kafka 	
	Deployed Docker images with Kubernetes and Helm Charts	
	Automated CI/CD pipelines with Jenkins	
02.2017 - 12.2017	Web Developer (Student Job) at Lyrehouse	Aachen
	 Contributed to WordPress projects with PHP, MySQL, and Docker 	
	 Improved the project by refactoring into MVC architecture 	
	 Involved in weekly Agile meetings 	
	Completed several reusable components	
Education		
Education		

09.2016 - 07.2018	RWTH Aachen University	Aachen
	Master of Science, Software Systems Engineering	
09.2011 - 06.2015	National Taiwan University	Taipei, Taiwan
	Bachelor of Business Administration, Information Management	

Skills

Kotlin, Java, Spring Boot, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RabbitMQ, Kubernetes, Sentry, ELK, New Relic, JavaScript, Vue

Languages

English, German, Chinese, Japanese